Tony Schwartz Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 1. Biographical and Personal Materials, 1931–2008, 10.2 linear feet
  - Publications about Tony Schwartz, 1951–2008
    - Publicity and press files, 1978–1988
      - 1984 (Box-folder 11/7)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 11/8)
      - 1986–1987 (Box-folder 11/9)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 11/10)
  - Tony Schwartz Collection documentation, 1966–1993 and undated
    Catalogs, inventories, databases, and reports that document the contents of the Tony Schwartz collection, including recorded sound, moving image, and textual materials. This subseries includes printed records from databases created by Schwartz as well as reports on his collection created by other individuals or institutions.
    - Miscellaneous tape summary lists, 1966-02-06, 1989-05-05–1990-03-30 (Box-folder 12/1)
      Summaries of recorded phone conversations, interviews, radio program content, voice talent, and health-related content.
    - Original audio tape catalogs, undated (Box-folder 12/2-4)
      Typed and handwritten lists and catalogs, some with overlapping sections, of audio tapes included in the collection. Includes descriptions of folk music recordings, radio recordings, and "V" series recordings ("various" material).
    - Documentation from original audio tape boxes, undated (Box-folder 12/5)
      Photocopies of tape labels, enclosures from tape boxes, and similar material.
    - Collection documentation prepared for the Library of Congress, 1993-01-15 (Box-folder 12/6-9)
      Correspondence, lists of political clients, and other collection documentation.
    - Documentation of David Hoffman tapes, 1987-02-03–1987-05-18 (Box-folder 13/1)
      Includes time codes and descriptions of tape contents.
    - Partial subject guide, undated (Box-folder 13/2)
      Photocopied lists of tape timings, apparently organized by subject or topic discussed.
    - Miscellaneous collection documentation, undated (Box-folder 13/3)
      Partial preliminary surveys, a hand-drawn map showing the locations of papers and media-based materials in Schwartz's home, and other material.
    - Compilation lists, 1989-05-05–1990-07-26 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Audio and video catalogs and databases, 1944–2004
      Prepared by Tony Schwartz and various employees, family members, and interns associated with him, these materials consist of lists and databases chiefly of audio and video recordings included in the collection, but also of his major clients and of awards he received.
      - Numerous formats, 1948-07-25–1997-10-27 (Box-folder 13/5)
        Includes descriptions of Schwartz sound recording series A-R, wire recordings, audio cassettes, films, "basement videos," paper documents, and awards received, as well as lists of clients relating to public health and safety issues, commercial products, and political campaigns.
      - B/Biography series sound recordings, 1962-12-17–1969-12 (Box-folder 13/6)
      - C/Commercial client series, binder 1, sound recordings, 1961-01-20–1996-10-09, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 13-14, Box 13, Box 14)
      - C/Commercial client series, binder 2, sound recordings, 1957–1993-03 (Box-folder 14/2-5)
      - C/Commercial client series, binder 3, sound recordings, 1960–1992-08-10 (Box-folder 15/1-4)
      - C/Commercial client series, binder 4, sound recordings, 1959-07-29–1998-06-09 (Box-folder 15/5-6)
      - S/Sounds series, binder 1, sound recordings, 1956–1989-10-19 (Box-folder 16/1-3)
      - S/Sounds series, binder 2, sound recordings, 1944–1990-07-23 (Box-folder 16/4-6)
      - M/Music series sound recordings, 1951-01-04–1963-11 (Box-folder 17/1)
      - MM/Marshall McLuhan series sound recordings, 1966-04-28–1997-03-17 (Box-folder 17/2)
      - RP/Radio program series sound recordings, 1960-02-25–1976-07-27 (Box-folder 17/3)
      - V/Voice series sound recordings, 1951-11-14–1990-01-23 (Box-folder 17/4-6)
      - T 3-inch tape reel series, 1950–1951-04-10 (Box-folder 17/7)
      - TV, 1-inch and 2-inch tape reels, 1970-10-20–1994-09-21 (Box-folder 18/1-3)
      - VHS videocassettes, 1965-08-13–2001-01-24, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 18-19, Box 18, Box 19)
      - Beta and U-Matic videocassettes, 1973-02-26–1997-09-29 (Box-folder 19/2)
      - Sound recording databases, 2004-06-29 (Box-folder 19/3)
        A CD-R and a zip disc containing databases that document Tony Schwartz's recordings.
      - Catalog of WNYC radio programs, binder 1, sound recordings, 1963-02-09–1970-12-15 (Box-folder 19/4-5)
      - Catalog of WNYC radio programs, binder 2, sound recordings, 1962-04-03–1976-03-30 (Box-folder 19/6-7)
      - Catalog of WNYC radio programs, binder 3, sound recordings, 1961-05-03–1976-06-08 (Box-folder 20/1)
      - List of WNYC radio program sound recordings, 1961-05-03–1976-06-08 (Box-folder 20/2)
        Compiled list of WNYC programs by Schwartz; includes his RP series numbers. Overlaps with descriptions from the original binders.
        See also WNYC business correspondence; radio scripts, correspondence, and research material in Schwartz's public service clients material; program guide, transcripts, and other publications-related material; and the WNYC subject file.
    - Preservation and historical assessment of the Tony Schwartz collection, 2004-02-08 (Box-folder 20/3-6)
      Report prepared by audio archivist Leslie C. Waffen for Tony and Reenah Schwartz.
    - Collection appraisal by Steve Johnson, 2004-11-15 (Box-folder 20/7)
      Financial appraisal prepared by Dr. Steven Johnson, including correspondence with Ann Weiss and a letter between Reenah Schwartz and "Mr. Stanhope."
  - Tony Schwartz material held in other archives, 1961–1997
    - Julian Kanter, Political Commercial Archives, 1980-07-12–1988-07-29 (Box-folder 21/1)
      Correspondence and articles related to the archive and its director, Julian Kanter.
    - Correspondence, inventory of material at Unitel Video, 1989-04-11–1989-01-28 (Box-folder 21/2)
      See also Martin Himmel Health Foundation material.
    - Museum Tinguely, 1961-01-01–1997-06-03 (Box-folder 21/3)
      Articles and correspondence on Jean Tinguely and the museum holding his works, as well as on the acquisition of Schwartz material.
  - Miscellaneous personal material, 1975–1997
    This subseries consists of material for which the context in Schwartz's collection could not be clearly determined. Photographs and other visual materials are also described in this subseries when they were of a generally personal nature but lacked sufficient context to describe elsewhere with confidence. Several of Schwartz's calendars are included as they document both personal and professional events and information that cannot be readily disentangled.
    - Articles and letters concerning the Ann Weiss photograph exhibition, "Eyes from the Ashes," 1989-04-30–1995-07-27 (Box-folder 21/4)
      Programs; Ann Weiss notes; articles from the Durham Morning Herald, the Raleigh News & Observer, and Philadelphia magazine; and letters from Weiss to Rabbi Jack Bemporad, from David Friend to Ann Weiss, and from Josephine Stamm (a general endorsement of the exhibition).
      See also Holocaust subject file and the Ann Weiss subject file.
    - Color photographs from the Ann Weiss exhibition, "Eyes from the Ashes," between 1989 and 1995 (Box 201)
      Six 4x6 inch color photographs, some of which show Ann Weiss, taken at an installment of the exhibition.
    - Color negatives of people in Tony Schwartz's home recording studio, and car and property damage, [circa 1980s?] (Box-folder 204/4)
      Eight 35 mm color negative strips showing two people [working?] in Schwartz's home recording studio, and damage to a car and property.
    - Negative images of a [New York City?] street taken through a fisheye lens, 1978 (Box-folder 204/5)
      One 35 mm black and white negative strip containing fisheye views of a city street (buildings and cars).
    - Documentation of surveillance on 56th Street, 1980-07-15–1980-07-19 (Box-folder 21/5-8)
      Surveillance instructions, written notes and observation logs, and photocopies of photographs.
    - Contact sheets of surveillance on 56th Street, 1980-07, RS 12620 PC1-PC10 (Box-folder 21/9)
      Ten black and white contact sheets.
      Contact sheets correspond to negatives in box 204/6-59 (item ID RS 12620 PN1-PN59).
    - Negatives of surveillance on 56th Street, 1980-07, RS 12620 PN1-PN59 (Box-folder 204/6-59)
      Fifty-four 35 mm black and white negative strips.
      Negatives correspond to the contact sheets in box 21/9 (item ID RS 12620 PC1-PC10).
    - Miscellaneous publicity-related material and photograph list, undated (Box-folder 21/10)
      Also includes a "Tony Schwartz" nameplate or sign.
    - Labeled, hand-drawn maps of New York City streets, undated (Box-folder 21/11)
      Drawn in pen and crayon.
    - Maps of the New York City and vicinity, 1975–1983 (Box-folder 21/12)
      Three maps: New York City and vicinity, greater New York, and Riverside Park (with guide).
    - Hagstrom map of the United States, RS 12620 G3 (Map-case RPM 00011)
      The map includes, by state, markers indicating the political campaigns in which Tony Schwartz was involved.
    - Miscellaneous black and white photographs of Tony Schwartz, various family members, and unidentified persons, undated (Box-folder 21/13)
      Fourteen black and white photographs, 8x10 inches and smaller, including promotional portraits of Tony Schwartz, posed photos and snapshots of Schwartz with family members and with unidentified people, a photo and photocopy of Schwartz recording the sound of an excavating machine or crane (Joseph Foldes, photographer), and photographs and a contact sheet of unidentified subjects and places.
      Photographers of the various promotional photographs include Michael Germana and "Constantine."
    - Framed photograph of Anton Schwartz on a picture phone, circa mid or late 1980s (Box 205)
      The image of Anton Schwartz appears on the screen of a Mitsubishi [VisiTel LU-500?] picture phone from the mid 1980s.
    - "Tony Schwartz at Work," original print by Don [F.?], [circa 1980s?] (Box-folder 219/4)
      Black and white original print, 15x11 inches, of Tony Schwartz editing a reel of tape in his home studio, with snarls of tape at his feet and a dog on the floor behind him.
      Artist's initials "D.F." signed on lower right corner of print.
      Handwritten in blue pencil along bottom edge: "Tony Schwartz at Work." Inscription: "With high regards. Fondly, Don."
    - Photograph of Tony Schwartz at work at a tape recorder, 1983-10 (Box-folder 219/5)
      Black and white photographic print, 13 1/2x9 1/2 inches, of Tony Schwartz editing a reel of tape.
      Photographer unidentified.
      From the markings on the reverse of the photograph, it appears that the image was intended for publication.
    - Photograph of Tony Schwartz in his home studio, circa 1998 (Box-folder 219/6)
      Three copies of a color portrait photograph by Jeanne Strongin. The picture, 11x8 1/2 inches, appears to have been printed on a laser printer.
    - Signed photograph to Tony and Reenah Schwartz, 1997-01-27 (Box-folder 219/7)
      Photograph of a woman and two men holding a commemorative plate for the "John Edgar Hoover Memorial Award, Distinguished Public Service."
      Handwritten on the photograph: "Tony & Reenah, with love from [Carl?] & Larry."
    - Photograph of Tony Schwartz and Kathleen Jamieson, circa late 1990s (Box-folder 219/8)
      Color photograph, 8 1/2x11 inches, that appears to have been printed on a laser printer.
    - Unidentified photograph by David Gahr, undated (Box-folder 219/9)
      Black and white 9x13 inch photographic print showing a group of people looking at an ornately framed portrait.
    - Photograph of a parade of circus elephants, undated (Box-folder 219/10)
      Color 8 1/2x11 inch photograph that appears to have been printed on a laser printer.
    - Unidentified poster of Tony Schwartz, undated (Box-folder 229/1)
      Unidentified black-and-white poster, 20x15 1/2 inches, of Tony Schwartz's face, which consists of multiple hand-drawn images of Schwartz and others listening to and recording sound.
    - Calendars, 1985-12-01–1987-12-31 (Box-folder 22/1-6)
      Three yearly calendars housed in six folders. Calendars include personal and business appointments, phone numbers, business cards, notes, and reminders for the years 1985 through 1987.
- Series 2. Business and Professional Materials, 1940–2005, 54 linear feet
  The Business and Professional Materials series contains files that relate to Schwartz's core business ventures. This includes general administrative documents such as appointment books, business cards, financial papers, and correspondence. These are followed by Schwartz's client files, consisting of correspondence, research materials, scripts, and other advertising ephemera; these clients include individuals and organizations of both political and commercial concerns, as well as numerous public awareness campaigns for causes that Schwartz took personal interest in. Following the client files is material related to Schwartz's business ventures beyond his core work as a media consultant; this includes his art and design work, radio programming, and his educational and lecture work.
  - General business, 1950–2005
    Includes documentation of Schwartz's daily business activities, such as appointment books, business cards, guest books, invoices, and client lists. Also includes contracts, release forms, faxes, and other business documents from Schwartz's production company, New Sounds, Inc.
    - Address book, undated (Box-folder 23/1)
    - Address books, 1951–1952 (Box-folder 23/2)
    - Agreement for proposed Schwartz memoir, 1992 (Box-folder 23/3)
    - Agreements, 1962–1998 (Box-folder 23/4)
      Includes an agreement with Publishing Industry Development Corp. (PIDC).
    - Appointment books, 1956–1968 (Box-folder 23/5-7)
    - Awards, 1992 (Box-folder 23/8)
    - Bell South Annual Report Project, 1992 (Box-folder 23/9)
    - Burlington Audio/Video Tapes, Inc., undated (Box-folder 23/10)
    - Business appointments, 1967–2002
      - 1967–1969 (Box-folder 24/1-4)
      - 1969–1970 (Box-folder 25/1-3)
      - 1971, (2 folders) (Box 25-26, Box 25, Box 26)
      - 1972–1973 (Box-folder 26/3-6)
      - 1974–1975 (Box-folder 27/1-6)
      - 1976–1978 (Box-folder 28/1-6)
      - 1978–1980 (Box-folder 29/1-5)
      - 1981–1984 (Box-folder 30/1-6)
      - 1986–1989 (Box-folder 31/1-6)
      - 1989–1992 (Box-folder 32/1-6)
      - 1992–1994 (Box-folder 33/1-6)
      - 1994–1996 (Box-folder 34/1-6)
      - 1997–2000 (Box-folder 35/1-6)
      - 2002 (Box-folder 36/1)
    - Business cards, undated (Box-folder 36/2-6)
    - Business cards, books 2 and 3, undated (Box-folder 37/1-2)
    - Business papers, 1984 (Box-folder 37/3)
      TV releases, Cinetel Productions, Inc.
    - Center for Media in the Public Interest (CMPI), 1989–1990 (Box-folder 37/4-6)
      Contains documents from attorney Irving M. Wall and Milton Goldin Company (fund raising consultants).
      See also CMPI business correspondence and CMPI publications.
    - Center for Media in the Public Interest (CMPI) brochure paste-ups, [1992-03-31?] (Box-folder 229/2)
      Three paste-ups (mechanicals), each 15x20 inches, containing black-and-white photographic images and text for a CMPI brochure. Each paste-up is overlaid with tissue on which layout instructions are written. Also in the file are several 8 1/2 x 11 inch proof sheets showing just the text of the brochure. Handwritten on the original envelope containing the materials (which was discarded due to preservation concerns) was the date "3-31-92."
    - Contacts, 1969-1998 and undated
      Includes contact information arranged originally by year, by name, and by type of contact (personal, political).
      - 1971 (Box-folder 37/7)
      - 1980 (Box-folder 38/1)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 38/2)
      - 1996–1998 (Box-folder 38/3-4)
      - undated (Box-folder 38/5)
      - A-L, undated, (1 folder) (Box 38-39, Box 38, Box 39)
      - M-Z, undated (Box-folder 39/2-3)
      - Clients, undated (Box-folder 39/4)
      - People, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 39-40, Box 39, Box 40)
      - Political, undated (Box-folder 40/3)
    - Contract fees, undated (Box-folder 40/4)
    - Contracts-Bell South, 1992 (Box-folder 40/5)
      The contact person was Harry Vardis.
    - Reverend John M. Culkin, 1969, and undated (Box-folder 40/6)
    - Daily calls, 1998–2002
      - 1998–1999 (Box-folder 40/7-8)
      - 1999–2002 (Box-folder 41/1-5)
    - Date book, 2002–2004 (Box-folder 41/6)
    - Document lists, 1994 (Box-folder 41/7)
    - "Ears Wide Open," 1999–2000 (Box-folder 41/8)
      A proposed documentary project about Tony Schwartz.
      See also "Ears Wide Open" article in People magazine.
    - East West Electronic Media Center, undated (Box-folder 41/9)
    - The Effect of the Microphone, undated (Box-folder 41/10)
      A journal with tabs made by Schwartz, but pages are mostly empty.
    - Employees, applications to work with Schwartz, 1986–1989 (Box-folder 41/11)
      Includes materials about David Haviland.
    - Equipment diagrams, 1960–1969 (Box-folder 41/12)
      Includes diagrams drawn by Tony Schwartz.
    - Equipment documentation, undated (Box-folder 42/1)
    - Equipment used or researched by Schwartz, 1991–1997 and undated
      - Equipment used or researched by Schwartz, 1991–1997 (Box-folder 42/2)
        Includes materials about Edward Canby Audio.
      - Patch bays with VU meters, undated (Box 206-207)
      - Teleprompter with handwritten script, undated (Box 208)
        Simple electric teleprompter containing handwritten script on a paper scroll. Some of the script is visible: "... the middle class in New York. They don't. [Word crossed out, illegible.] That's the kid of New York I want. Isn't that the kind of New York ..."
      - Sixty-second timer, undated (Box 209)
        Sixty-second timer with remote power switch.
    - Finances, undated (Box-folder 42/3)
    - Guest Book #1, 1968–2004 (Box-folder 42/4)
    - Guest Book #2, 1982–2005 (Box-folder 42/5)
    - Guest book (blank), undated (Box-folder 42/6)
    - Humphrey for President Committee, 1968 (Box-folder 43/1)
    - International Film & TV Festival of New York entry forms, 1988 (Box-folder 43/2)
    - International Radio Festival of New York entry forms, 1987 (Box-folder 43/3)
    - Invitations, 1989–1997 (Box-folder 43/4)
    - Invoices, 1976–1998 (Box-folder 43/5)
    - Jury service, 1981 (Box-folder 43/6)
    - Marshall McLuhan estate, 1969–1996 (Box-folder 43/7)
    - Media Peace Corp business, 1990 (Box-folder 43/8)
    - Messenger, Federal Express, etc., 1989–1993 (Box-folder 43/9)
    - Minutes from Legend Recordings, Inc. meeting, 1954 (Box-folder 43/10)
    - New Sounds, Inc., 1968-1997, and undated
      Tony Schwartz production company.
      - Company profile, 1987 (Box-folder 43/11)
      - Contact sheets, undated (Box-folder 43/12)
      - Contracts, 1968–1993 (Box-folder 43/13)
      - Faxes sent, 1994–1997 (Box-folder 43/14)
      - Floor plans, undated (Box-folder 43/15)
      - General, 1995 (Box-folder 43/16)
      - IAR permission requests, 1997 (Box-folder 43/17)
      - Label masters, undated (Box-folder 43/18)
      - Release forms, 1994 (Box-folder 43/19)
      - Stationery, undated (Box-folder 43/20)
      - Stationery, lettering, fonts, undated (Box-folder 43/21)
      - Blank synchronizing sheets, undated (Box-folder 229/3)
        A pad, 7x21 inches, of blank, printed sound synchronizing sheets, with Schwartz's name and "New Sounds, Inc.," followed by the company address and phone number, printed at the top of each sheet. The sheets are intended for synchronizing time of recorded content (in seconds) with number of feet on an audio tape.
    - Notes about sound, preparing for clients, 1970–1972 (Box-folder 44/1)
    - New York D.A. Detectives PBA, 1985 (Box-folder 44/2)
    - Permission forms (Joseph Meehan), 1988 (Box-folder 44/3)
    - Phone numbers, undated (Box-folder 44/4-5)
    - Planned Reactions, Inc., 1955, 1970, 1995 (Box-folder 44/6)
      See also Media Lobbying, Inc.
    - Planned Reactions, Inc., lettering, fonts, business card draft, circa 1970–1980s (Box-folder 220/1)
    - Proposal on antisemitism, 1993 (Box-folder 44/7)
    - Publicity, undated (Box-folder 44/8)
    - Radio, 1977–1994 (Box-folder 44/9)
    - The Radio Foundation, 1981 (Box-folder 44/10)
    - Miscellaneous receipts, 1986–1995 (Box-folder 44/11)
    - Landco Labs, Inc. receipts, 1989–1991 (Box-folder 44/12)
    - Movielab, Inc. receipts, 1987 (Box-folder 44/13)
    - Resumes and letters of recommendation, 1982–1999 (Box-folder 44/14)
      Includes letter of recommendation for Schwartz's long-time assistant, John Carey.
    - Paul Robeson collection, 1995–1999 (Box-folder 44/15)
    - Royalties and release forms, 1975–1997 (Box-folder 44/16)
    - Business cards for various services, undated (Box-folder 45/1)
    - Stationery, undated (Box-folder 45/2-3)
    - Stationery, lettering, fonts, undated (Box-folder 45/4)
    - Stationery, lettering, fonts for Cable Radio, undated (Box-folder 220/2)
    - Stationery, lettering, fonts for EMC (Environmental Media Consultants), undated (Box-folder 220/3)
    - Lettering, fonts for Sound by Tony Schwartz, undated (Box-folder 220/4)
    - Rubber and metal stamps and plates for business and promotional use, undated (Box 221)
      Artifact storage box containing eight stamps, made of rubber on wood, rubber on metal, or plastic; measuring 3 inches highx3 inches wide or smaller; most bearing Tony Schwartz's name. Also contains a metal address [stamper?], a bracket of unknown use, a 3x3 inch wooden stamping block promoting Schwartz's limited edition LP, Standing Here at the Present Time, and a 3x4 inch copper-on-wood printing plate showing Tony Schwartz at work at a tape console.
    - Stock certificates, 1955, and undated (Box-folder 45/5)
    - Stocks, 1964–1975 (Box-folder 45/6)
    - Talent, undated (Box-folder 45/7)
    - Numbers and addresses relating to talent, undated (Box-folder 45/8)
    - "Talking Back" project, 1994–1995 (Box-folder 46/1)
      Mike Pertschuk, Frank Luntz memo.
    - Tax, gifts, 1980–1983 (Box-folder 46/2)
    - Telephone and talent book, 1950–2000 (Box-folder 46/3)
    - WATS Marketing of America, Inc., 1989 (Box-folder 46/4)
  - Business correspondence, 1940–2005
    Includes correspondence to and from Schwartz on a range of topics, such as Schwartz's speaking engagements, seminars, interviews, awards, and participation in committees and conferences. Notable correspondents include Bob Landers, Marshall McLuhan, the Kitchen Sisters, Center for Media in the Public Interest (CMPI), and Michael Pertschuk.
    - Miscellaneous business correspondence, 1940–2005, undated
      - 1940, 1952–1965 (Box-folder 46/5)
        Written on original folder: "Important letters to Schwartz."
      - 1966–1969 (Box-folder 46/6-8)
      - 1970–1985 (Box-folder 47/1-7)
      - 1986–1997 (Box-folder 48/1-6)
      - 1998–2005, and undated (Box-folder 49/1-5)
    - Correspondence concerning proposed projects, 2000 (Box-folder 49/6)
    - Letters from Tony Schwartz, 1973–1999 (Box-folder 49/7)
    - Correspondence from out-of-town agencies, 1967–1970 (Box-folder 49/8)
    - ABC, 1988–1999 (Box-folder 49/9)
    - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, 1999 (Box-folder 49/10)
      Includes a letter from Sheila Schwartz.
    - American Cancer Society, 1969–1989 (Box-folder 49/11)
    - Association of Independent Colleges and Universities in Massachusetts (AICUM), 1983 (Box-folder 49/12)
    - BBC Production, 1991–2002 (Box-folder 49/13)